James R. Priest

5111 Princess Anne Road, La Canada, CA 91011 • Cell 626-240-9970 Email james-priest@outlook.com • Website https://james-priest.github.io

SUMMARY

Senior Front End / Full Stack Web Developer with 20 years of experience | JavaScript, React.js, .NET, Node.js, DB

SKILLS

Language: JavaScript, C#, SQL, Regular Expressions Web: HTML5, CSS3, DOM, Bootstrap, REST API Database: SQL Server, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB **IDE:** VS Code, Visual Studio, Chrome Developer Tools

Cloud: Firebase, AWS, Azure DevOps, RestDB.io

Build: NPM, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, Parcel, Yeoman

Framework: React.js, Redux, ASP.NET, Node.js, jQuery

UI Design: Responsive UI/UX, Accessibility

Data: Stored Procedures, Functions, Triggers, Views

Distributed Version Control: Git, GitHub, SVN

Hosting: Netlify, Heroku, Azure Web

Static Site Generator: Gatsby, Jekyll, GitHub Pages

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Application Developer / Technology Director Velodea

Pasadena, CA

04/2006 - 03/2017

- Served as Solutions Architect, Programming Lead, and Database Developer for digital marketing firm.
- Successfully built over 70 website solutions and marketing campaigns for Fortune 500 companies including Shell, Qualcomm, Sprint, Maserati, Fox, Miramax, ABC, J. Walter Thompson, & Edelman.
- Designed large-scale medical management system to track & schedule education of 85,000 students.

Lead Developer & Founder

La Canada, CA

devAware Technology Solutions

07/2002 - 03/2006

- Excelled in building custom Web, Windows, & .NET application systems for various corporate clients.
- Hired by Sony to build advanced kiosk application for VIAO laptops. Had successful nationwide rollout.
- Engineered web & desktop platform to promote major motion picture releases for Fox & Miramax.

Lead Software Developer

Milan, Italy, Los Angeles, CA

The Velodea Group / Bleu22 Studios

07/2000 - 07/2002

- Led the product development team of multi-national digital start-up with offices in Milan & Los Angeles.
- Developed real-time web analytics platform to provide behavioral tracking & custom reporting.
- Built proprietary asset & client management system. Licensed by Sony, Qualcomm, & Shell Oil.

Release Program Manager

Redmond, WA

Microsoft

11/1998 – 06/2000

- Designed mission-critical app suite to manage thousands of software releases to the web each month.
- Build web-based training system to provide CBT to employees and non-technical business owners.
- Engineered tracking & query system to manage media shipments of software to third-party vendors.

EDUCATION

DeVry University	Pomona, CA
Bachelor of Computer Information Systems (BSc CIS)	Graduated with Honors – GPA 3.52/4.00

CERTIFICATIONS

React Nanodegree (React, Redux, React Native), Udacity	6-month term	June 2019
Google Mobile Web Specialist Nanodegree, Udacity	6-month term	October 2018
JavaScript Algorithms & Data Structures, freeCodeCamp	300 hours	December 2017
Responsive Web Design, freeCodeCamp	300 hours	July 2017

James R. Priest

5111 Princess Anne Road, La Canada, CA 91011 • Cell 626-240-9970 Email james-priest@outlook.com • Website https://james-priest.github.io

RECENT PROJECTS

Mobile Flashcards App

June 2019

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2KqJE3i Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2Irc8aY



React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Redux Thunk, Expo, Animations, Notifications

Triathlon Fitness Tracker

May 2019

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2MTVhSc Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2FhBE06



React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Geolocation, Notifications, Expo

Would You Rather Game

April 2019

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2MVL2Ng Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2RkLflc



React, Redux, React Router, Redux Thunk, Auth, REST API, RestDB, Semantic-UI-React

Restaurant Review App

December 2018

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2x1xwwL Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2KYE0EJ



PWA, IndexedDB, Cache API, Promise API, Service Worker, REST API, RestDB

CSS Grid Learning App

June 2018

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2WR0Gcz Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2KpZ3AB



JavaScript ES6, CSS3 Animations, RegEx, Advanced DOM Manipulation

Weather Forecast App

March 2018

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2IphkM8
Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2MRbgQP



HTML5, Geolocation API, Semantic UI, CSS3 Animations, Async Web API